Inventory of the Department of Classical Studies Records 1840-2007
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Department of Classical Studies Records 1840-[ongoing] 1937-2007
Special Collections Research Center
00/02/01/22/UA 158
0.40
The collection includes subject files from 1963-1976 related to language placement, summer sessions, and a self-study of the Department of Classical Studies at the College of William and Mary. It also contains publications such as fliers and brochures from the Summer Institute in Latin and the Humanities. The collection also includes questions from William and Mary classes dated to 1840-1841.
Dept. of Classical Studies arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Custodial History
A portion of this collection was previously part of the University Archives Publications Collection. The following items were transferred from the College Papers Collection:-A 1938 letter from the Ancient and Modern Languages department to a prospective student.-The 1937 Latin Tournament questions of the Virginia Classical Association held at the College of William and Mary on April 17, 1937.
Historical Note
Information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Dept. of Classical Studies.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes subject files from 1963-1976 related to language placement, summer sessions, and a self-study of the Department of Classical Studies at the College of William and Mary. It also contains publications such as fliers and brochures from the Summer Institute in Latin and the Humanities. The collection also includes questions from William and Mary classes dated to 1840-1841.
Additional Information
Related Materials
Department of Modern Languages (UA 211), Office of the Dean of Arts and Sciences (UA 310), and various other administrative records.
Information about related materials is available at http://guides.swem.wm.edu/wm
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
College of William and Mary. Dept. of Classical Studies
Genre/Form of Material:
Fliers (printed matter); Publications
Topical Term:
College of William and Mary--History--20th century.; College of William and Mary--History--21st century
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Acc. 1998.045, 1961-1976; id56165
  - Language Placement, 1963-1973; id56205 (Folder 1)
  - List of Authors Contained in Migne's Patrologia Latina, 1961; id56207 (Folder 2)
  - Self-Study Department, 1963-1972; id56208 (Folder 3)
  - Summer Sessions, 1967-1976; id56209 (Folder 4)
- Publications, 1937-[ongoing]; id43348
  - id37271 (Box 1)
    - Fliers, etc., 1989-[ongoing]; id37272 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Summer Institute in Latin and the Humanities, 1972-1975; id37273 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Welcome Letter and Latin Tournament Questions, 1937-1938; id70389 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Questions, 1840-1841; id82586 (Box 1, Folder 4)